




	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on CC 310 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/1-review-control-flow-i-o-and-exceptions/4-python/index.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on CC 310 Textbook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/1-review-control-flow-i-o-and-exceptions/4-python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Syntax Overview</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/1-review-control-flow-i-o-and-exceptions/4-python/1-syntax-overview/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/1-review-control-flow-i-o-and-exceptions/4-python/1-syntax-overview/index.html</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s discuss some of the basic concepts we need to understand about the Python programming language.
Program Structure To begin, let&amp;rsquo;s look at a simple Hello World program written in Python:
This program contains multiple important parts:
First, we define a function called main(). Python does not require us to do this, since we can write our code directly in the file and it will execute. However, since we are going to be building larger programs in this course, it is a good idea to start using functions now.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Run Code</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/1-review-control-flow-i-o-and-exceptions/4-python/2-run-code/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/1-review-control-flow-i-o-and-exceptions/4-python/2-run-code/index.html</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video
Now that we&amp;rsquo;ve written our first Python program, we must run the program to see the fruits of our labors. There are many different ways to do this using the Codio platform. We&amp;rsquo;ll discuss each of them in detail here.
Terminal Codio includes a built-in Linux terminal, which allows us to perform actions directly on a command-line interface just like we would on an actual computer running Linux.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Debugging</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/1-review-control-flow-i-o-and-exceptions/4-python/3-debugging/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/1-review-control-flow-i-o-and-exceptions/4-python/3-debugging/index.html</guid>
      <description>Codio also includes an integrated debugger, which is very helpful when we want to determine if there is an error in our code. We can also use the debugger to see what values are stored in each variable at any point in our program.
To use the debugger, find the Debug Menu at the top of the Codio window. It is to the right of the Run Menu we&amp;rsquo;ve already been using.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Variables</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/1-review-control-flow-i-o-and-exceptions/4-python/4-variables/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/1-review-control-flow-i-o-and-exceptions/4-python/4-variables/index.html</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video
A variable in a programming language is an abstraction that allows storing one value in each instant of time, but this value can change along with the program execution. A variable can be represented as a box holding a value. If the variable is a container, e.g., a list (or array or vector), a matrix, a tuple, or a set of values, each box in the container contains a single value.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conditionals</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/1-review-control-flow-i-o-and-exceptions/4-python/5-conditionals/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/1-review-control-flow-i-o-and-exceptions/4-python/5-conditionals/index.html</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video
The conditional statement, also known as the If-Then statement, is used to control the program&amp;rsquo;s flow by checking the value of a Boolean statement and determining if a block of code should be executed based on that value. This is the simplest conditional instruction. If the condition is true, the block enclosed within the statement is executed. If it is false, then the code in the block is skipped.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Loops</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/1-review-control-flow-i-o-and-exceptions/4-python/6-loops/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/1-review-control-flow-i-o-and-exceptions/4-python/6-loops/index.html</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video
Loops are another way we can control the flow of our program, this time by repeating steps based on a given criteria. A computer is able to repeat the same instructions many times. There are several ways to tell a computer to repeat a sequence of instructions:
Repeat an infinite number of times, e.g. while true. This construct is useful in software applications such as servers that will offer a service.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exercise 1</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/1-review-control-flow-i-o-and-exceptions/4-python/7-exercise-1/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/1-review-control-flow-i-o-and-exceptions/4-python/7-exercise-1/index.html</guid>
      <description>At this point, we&amp;rsquo;ve covered enough material to build a simple program. So, let&amp;rsquo;s see if we can complete the following example program before continuing.
Problem Statement Write a program that reads an integer from either the terminal, or a file if one is provided as a command-line argument. It should not worry about handling any exceptions encountered.
The program should compute and print the sum of all integers from 1 up to and including the integer provided as input, except those integers which are evenly divisible by 3.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lists</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/1-review-control-flow-i-o-and-exceptions/4-python/8-lists/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/1-review-control-flow-i-o-and-exceptions/4-python/8-lists/index.html</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video
^[File:USPS Post office boxes 1.jpg. (2017, May 17). Wikimedia Commons, the free media repository. Retrieved 18:17, November 5, 2018 from https://commons.wikimedia.org/w/index.php?title=File:USPS_Post_office_boxes_1.jpg&amp;amp;oldid=244476438.]
Arrays allow us to store multiple values in the same variable, using an index to determine which value we wish to store or retrieve from the array. We can think of arrays like a set of post office boxes. Each one has the same physical address, the post office, but within the post office we can find an individual box based on its own box number.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Variable Roles</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/1-review-control-flow-i-o-and-exceptions/4-python/9-variable-roles/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/1-review-control-flow-i-o-and-exceptions/4-python/9-variable-roles/index.html</guid>
      <description>Variables in our programs can be used in a variety of different roles. The simplest role for any variable is to store a value that does not change throughout the entire program. Most variables, however, fit into one of several roles throughout the program.
To help us understand these roles, let&amp;rsquo;s review them in detail here. As we move forward in this course, we&amp;rsquo;ll see many different data structures that use variables in these ways, so it helps to know each of them early on!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strings</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/1-review-control-flow-i-o-and-exceptions/4-python/10-strings/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/1-review-control-flow-i-o-and-exceptions/4-python/10-strings/index.html</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video
Strings are another very important data type in programming. A string is simply a set of characters that represent text in our programs. We can then write programs that use and manipulate strings in a variety of ways, allowing us to easily work with textual data.
Strings in Flowcharts &amp;amp; Pseudocode The table below lists the flowchart blocks used to represent strings, as well as the corresponding pseudocode:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exceptions</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/1-review-control-flow-i-o-and-exceptions/4-python/11-exceptions/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/1-review-control-flow-i-o-and-exceptions/4-python/11-exceptions/index.html</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video
An exception is an error that a program encounters when it is running. While some errors cannot be dealt with directly by the program, many of these exceptions can be caught and handled directly in our programs.
Exceptions in Flowcharts &amp;amp; Pseudocode There isn&amp;rsquo;t really a standard way to display exceptions in flowcharts and pseudocode, but we can easily create a system that works well for our needs. Below are the flowchart blocks and pseudocode examples we&amp;rsquo;ll use in this course to represent exceptions and exception handling:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I/O</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/1-review-control-flow-i-o-and-exceptions/4-python/12-i-o/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/1-review-control-flow-i-o-and-exceptions/4-python/12-i-o/index.html</guid>
      <description>One of the major features of a modern computer is the ability to store and retrieve data from the computer&amp;rsquo;s file system. So, we need to be able to access the file system in our code in order to build useful programs. Thankfully, most modern programming languages include a way to do this.
I/O in Flowcharts &amp;amp; Pseudocode Most operations working with files in code take the form of method calls.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Documentation</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/1-review-control-flow-i-o-and-exceptions/4-python/13-documentation/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/1-review-control-flow-i-o-and-exceptions/4-python/13-documentation/index.html</guid>
      <description>It is important both to easily grasp the design choice and the code structure of a project even long after it has been completed. The documentation process starts by commenting the code. Code comments are usually intended for software developers and aim at clarifying the code by giving details of how it works. They are usually performed using inline or multiple lines comments using the language syntax.
Single Line Comments As we&amp;rsquo;ve seen before, we can add single-line comments to our Python programs using a hash symbol # before a line in our source file:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Style</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/1-review-control-flow-i-o-and-exceptions/4-python/14-style/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/1-review-control-flow-i-o-and-exceptions/4-python/14-style/index.html</guid>
      <description>Style Guide To make your code easier to read, many textbooks and companies use a style guide that defines some of the formating rules that you should follow in your source code. In Python, these rules are very important, as the structure of your code is defined by the layout. We&amp;rsquo;ll learn more about that in a later module.
For this book, most of the examples will be presented using the guidelines in the Style Guide for Python .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exercise 2</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/1-review-control-flow-i-o-and-exceptions/4-python/15-exercise-2/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/1-review-control-flow-i-o-and-exceptions/4-python/15-exercise-2/index.html</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s build another sample program to review the content we&amp;rsquo;ve covered thus far.
Problem Statement Write a program that accepts three files as command line arguments. The first two represent input files, and the third one represents the desired output file. If there aren&amp;rsquo;t three arguments provided, either input file is not an existing file, or the output file is an existing directory, print &amp;ldquo;Invalid Arguments&amp;rdquo; and exit the program. The output file may be an existing file, since it will be overwritten.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>