




  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Priority Queues :: CC 310 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/12-priority-queues/</link>
    <description>A queue that efficiently sorts as data is inserted!</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/12-priority-queues/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/12-priority-queues/01-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/12-priority-queues/01-intro/</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video The next data structure we will cover is heaps. The heaps discussed in this course are not to be confused with heaps which refer to garbage collection in certain coding languages. Heaps are good for situations were we will need to frequently access and update the highest (or lowest) priority item in a set. For example, heaps are a good data structure to use in Prim’s algorithm. In Prim’s algorithm, we repeatedly got the smallest edge, removed the smallest edge, and then added to and sorted the list of edges.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Node Relationships</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/12-priority-queues/02-nodes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/12-priority-queues/02-nodes/</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Heaps can be viewed in two forms: as a tree or as an array. We will use the array style in code but we can have the tree structure in the back of our mind to help understand the order of the data. Here is an example of the heap as a tree on the left and the heap as an array on the right.&#xA;The root of the heap will always be the first element.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Priority Queues</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/12-priority-queues/03-priority-queues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/12-priority-queues/03-priority-queues/</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video A natural implementation of heaps is priority queues.&#xA;A priority queue is a data structure which contains elements and each element has an associated key value. The key for an element corresponds to its importance. In real world applications, these can be used for prioritizing work tickets, emails, and much more.&#xA;We can use a heap to organize this data for us.&#xA;As with heaps, we can have min-priority queues and max-priority queues.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dijkstras</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/12-priority-queues/04-dijkstras/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/12-priority-queues/04-dijkstras/</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Video Slides&#xA;A good application of priority queues is finding the shortest path in a graph. A common algorithm for this is Dijkstra’s algorithm.&#xA;Edsger Dijkstra was a Dutch computer scientist who researched many fields. He is credited for his work in physics, programming, software engineering, and as a systems scientist. His motivation for this algorithm in particular was to be able to find the shortest path between two cities.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>