




  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Old Conetnt :: CC 310 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/10-graphs/old/</link>
    <description>Old Content</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/10-graphs/old/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UML - Graph Node</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/10-graphs/old/4-uml---graph-node/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/10-graphs/old/4-uml---graph-node/</guid>
      <description>In this representation, we will have an array of graph node objects. We will first cover the UML for the graph node objects and then discuss the graph functions and attributes.&#xA;Attributes item: the value that the node contains. index: the index of the node. edges: ordered pairs (e, w) where this node is the source, e is the target node index, and w is the weight of the edge as a double.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Node and Edge Functions</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/10-graphs/old/6-node-and-edge-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/10-graphs/old/6-node-and-edge-functions/</guid>
      <description>add node: will add a node to the graph with the given value if our graph still has room. Finding a location for the node will be the same procedure as the matrix graph. If we find an open spot to add the node, we will instantiate a new graph node and insert it into the nodes attribute. function ADDNODE(VALUE) IDX = -1 for NODE in NODES if NODE is VALUE return NODE&#39;s index if NODE has no entry and IDX is -1 IDX = NODE&#39;s index if IDX is not -1 NEWNODE = graph node with VALUE and IDX for input add NEWNODE to NODES at position IDX increment SIZE return IDX remove node: will remove a node to the graph with the given value if our graph has the node.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/10-graphs/old/7-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/10-graphs/old/7-summary/</guid>
      <description>In this module, we introduced a new way to store the graph data structure. Thus, we now have two ways to work with graphs, in lists and in matrices:&#xA;List Representation Matrix Representation While these methods show the same information, there are cases when one way may be more desirable than the other.&#xA;We discussed how a sparse graph is better suited for a list representation and a dense graph is better suited for a matrix representation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UML</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/10-graphs/old/8-uml/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/10-graphs/old/8-uml/</guid>
      <description>Attributes nodes: This will keep track of the nodes which are in our graph as well as the node values. The nodes can have any type of value such as numbers, characters, and even other data structures. edges: This will keep track of the edges which are in our graph. size: This will keep track of the number of nodes that are active in our graph. Upon initialization, we will initialize nodes to be an empty array of size capacity, edges to be an empty two-dimensional array with dimensions capacity by capacity and size to be zero as we start with no actual nodes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Node and Edge Functions</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/10-graphs/old/9-node-and-edge-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/10-graphs/old/9-node-and-edge-functions/</guid>
      <description>add node: will add a node to the graph with the given value if our graph still has room. Procedurally, we will try to put the node in the first empty place we find. To do this, we start with IDX equal to negative one then loop through all of the indexes of the graphs nodes attribute. At each index, we check if that entry is equal to the value we are trying to add.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>