




  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Graphs :: CC 310 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/10-graphs/</link>
    <description>Representing data in a graph!</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/10-graphs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/10-graphs/01-graph-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/10-graphs/01-graph-intro/</guid>
      <description>The next data structure we will introduce is a graph.&#xA;Graphs are multidimensional data structures that can represent many different types of data. We can use graphs to represent electronic circuits and wiring, transportation routes, and networks such as the Internet or social groups.&#xA;A popular and fun use of graphs is to build connections between people such as Facebook friends or even connections between performers. One example is the parlor game Six Degrees of Kevin Bacon.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Terms I</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/10-graphs/02-graph-terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/10-graphs/02-graph-terms/</guid>
      <description>We will discuss some of the basic terminology associated with graphs. Some of this vocabulary should feel familiar from the trees section; trees are a specific type of graph!&#xA;Nodes: Node is the general term for a structure which contains an item. Size: The size of a graph is the number of nodes. Capacity: The capacity of a graph is the maximum number of nodes. Info Nodes can be, but are not limited to the following examples: - physical locations (IE Manhattan, Topeka, Salina), - computer components (IE CPU, GPU, RAM), or - people (IE Kevin Bacon, Laurence Fishburne, Emma Stone)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graph Features</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/10-graphs/03-graph-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/10-graphs/03-graph-features/</guid>
      <description>While trees are a type of graph, graphs can have more functionality than trees. For example, recall that to be a single tree, there could be no disconnected pieces.&#xA;Connectedness: Graphs do not require being fully connected. There can be disconnected portions within a graph. For example, the following graph shows all of the students in a sophomore biology class. There is an edge between two student nodes if they are Facebook friends.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weighted Graphs</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/10-graphs/04-weighted/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/10-graphs/04-weighted/</guid>
      <description>A weighted graph is a graph which has weights associated with the edges. These weights quantify the relationships, so they can represent dollars, minutes, miles, and many other factors which our data may depend upon.&#xA;Weights are not limited to physical quantities; they can also be our own defined similarity in text, product types, and anything for which we can create a similarity measure for. Let’s look at concrete weights using the Amtrak example.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Directed Graphs</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/10-graphs/05-directed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/10-graphs/05-directed/</guid>
      <description>A directed graph is a graph that has a direction associated with each edge. For example, trees are a directed graph. The edge orientation will imply a fixed direction that we can move about nodes. As with trees, the flat end of the arrow will represent the origin and the arrowhead will represent the destination. If an edge has no arrowheads, then it is assumed that we can traverse both directions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Example</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/10-graphs/06-example1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/10-graphs/06-example1/</guid>
      <description>In the following graph, we have an example of a weighted and directed map. This map represents a zoo train where each node represents a station and each edge is a part of the track. Zoo guests can get on and off wherever they desire.&#xA;This graph is weighted as guests must pay the associated fee for each part of the track. Our example train also has a one way direction in most cases.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matrix Representation</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/10-graphs/07-matrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/10-graphs/07-matrix/</guid>
      <description>The first way that we can represent graphs is as matrices. In a matrix representation of a graph, we will have an array with all the nodes and a matrix to depict the edges. The matrix that depicts the edges is called the adjacency matrix.&#xA;To build the adjacency matrix, we go through the nodes and edges. If there is an edge with weight w going from i to j, then we put w in the (i,j) spot in our adjacency matrix.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/10-graphs/08-list-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/10-graphs/08-list-intro/</guid>
      <description>In the previous module, we introduced graphs and a matrix-based implementation. For this module, we will continue working with graphs and change our implementation to lists.&#xA;Why Another Implementation? When using graphs, a lot of situational variation can occur. Some graphs can have a few nodes with many edges, many nodes with few edges, and so on. When we use the matrix implementation, we initialize a matrix with the number of columns and rows equal to the number of nodes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>List Representation</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/10-graphs/09-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/10-graphs/09-list/</guid>
      <description>In the matrix representation, we had an array of the node items. In the list representation, we will have an array of node objects. Each node object will keep track of the node item, the node index, and the outgoing edges.&#xA;The item can be any object and the index will be a value within our capacity. The edges will be a list of pairs where the first entry is the index of the target node and the second entry is the weight of the edge.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dense VS Sparse</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/10-graphs/10-dense-sparse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/10-graphs/10-dense-sparse/</guid>
      <description>When considering which implementation to use, we need to consider the connectivity in our graph. The terms that we use to describe the connectedness are dense and sparse.&#xA;Dense Graph: A dense graph is a graph in which there is a large number of edges. Typically in a dense graph, the number of edges is close to the maximum number of edges. Sparse Graph: A sparse graph is a graph in which there is a small number of edges.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>List Graph UML</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/10-graphs/11-graph-uml/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/10-graphs/11-graph-uml/</guid>
      <description>Attributes nodes: This will keep track of the nodes which are in our graph as well as the node values. The nodes can have any type of value such as numbers, characters, and even other data structures. size: This will keep track of the number of nodes that are active in our graph. Upon initialization, we will initialize nodes to be an empty array with dimension capacity and size to be zero as we start with no actual nodes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/10-graphs/12-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/10-graphs/12-summary/</guid>
      <description>In this module, we have introduced the graph data structure. We also looked at how we would implement a graph using a matrix representation. We introduced the following new concepts in this module:&#xA;Directed Graphs: A directed graph is a graph that has a direction associated with each edge. The flat end of the arrow will represent the origin and the arrowhead will represent the destination. If an edge has no arrowheads, then it is assumed that we can traverse both directions.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>