




	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Review Object Oriented Programming on CC 310 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/2-review-object-oriented-programming/index.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Review Object Oriented Programming on CC 310 Textbook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/2-review-object-oriented-programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Object-Oriented Programming</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/2-review-object-oriented-programming/1-object-oriented-programming/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/2-review-object-oriented-programming/1-object-oriented-programming/index.html</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video
^[File:CPT-OOP-inheritance.svg. (2014, June 26). Wikimedia Commons, the free media repository. Retrieved 01:22, January 14, 2020 from https://commons.wikimedia.org/w/index.php?title=File:CPT-OOP-inheritance.svg&amp;amp;oldid=127549650.]
Object-oriented programming uses the idea of objects and classes to provide many improvements over other programming paradigms. The key concept of object-oriented programming - encapsulation - allows our data and the operations that manipulate that data to be bundled together within a single object.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Functions</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/2-review-object-oriented-programming/2-functions/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/2-review-object-oriented-programming/2-functions/index.html</guid>
      <description>Functions are small pieces of reusable code that allow you to divide complex programs into smaller subprograms. Ideally, functions perform a single task and return a single value. (It should be noted that some programming languages allow for procedures, which are similar to functions but return no values. Except for the return value, it is safe to group them with functions in our discussion below.)
Functions can be thought of as black boxes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Classes and Objects</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/2-review-object-oriented-programming/3-classes-and-objects/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/2-review-object-oriented-programming/3-classes-and-objects/index.html</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video
As you might guess from its name, object-oriented programming languages are made to create and manipulate entities called objects. But what exactly are these objects? Objects were created to help decompose large complex programs with a lot of complex data into manageable parts.
Info Object An object is a programming entity that contains related data and behavior.
A good example of an object is dog. But not just any dog, or all dogs, but a specific dog.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Information Hiding</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/2-review-object-oriented-programming/4-information-hiding/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/2-review-object-oriented-programming/4-information-hiding/index.html</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video
Two of the most powerful concepts in object orientation are encapsulation and information hiding.
Encapsulation is capturing both data and behavior into a single object. Information hiding is restricting access to some of the data and behavior of an object. Encapsulation enables information hiding, and information hiding allows us to simplify the interface used to interact with an object. Instead of needing to know everything about a particular class of objects in order to use or interact with those objects.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inheritance</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/2-review-object-oriented-programming/5-inheritance/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/2-review-object-oriented-programming/5-inheritance/index.html</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video
Polymorphism Polymorphsim is a concept that describes the fact that similar objects tend to behave in similar ways, even if they are not exactly alike. For example, if we might have a set of shapes such as a square, a circle, and a rhombus. While each shape shares certain attributes like having an area and a perimeter. However, each shape is also unique and may have differing number of sides and angles between those sides, or in the case of a circle, a diameter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Associations</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/2-review-object-oriented-programming/6-associations/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/2-review-object-oriented-programming/6-associations/index.html</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video
For object &amp;lsquo;a&amp;rsquo; to be able to call a method in object &amp;lsquo;b&amp;rsquo;, object &amp;lsquo;a&amp;rsquo; must have a reference (a pointer, or the address of) object &amp;lsquo;b&amp;rsquo;. In many cases, objects &amp;lsquo;a&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;b&amp;rsquo; will be in a long-term relationship so that one or both objects will need to store the reference to the other in an attribute. When an object holds a reference to another object in an attribute, we call this a link.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/2-review-object-oriented-programming/7-java/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/2-review-object-oriented-programming/7-java/index.html</guid>
      <description>Welcome! This page is the main page for Java</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/2-review-object-oriented-programming/8-python/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/2-review-object-oriented-programming/8-python/index.html</guid>
      <description>Welcome! This page is the main page for Python</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Object Oriented Programming Summary</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/2-review-object-oriented-programming/9-object-oriented-programming-summary/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc310/2-review-object-oriented-programming/9-object-oriented-programming-summary/index.html</guid>
      <description>This chapter covered the rest of the programming basics we&amp;rsquo;ll need to know before starting on the new content of this course. By now we should be pretty familiar with the basic syntax of the language we&amp;rsquo;ve chosen, as well as the concepts of classes, objects, inheritance, and polymorphism in object-oriented programming. Finally, we&amp;rsquo;ve explored the Model-View-Controller (MVC) architecture, which will be used extensively in this course.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>