




  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hash Tables :: CC 310 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/07-hash-tables/</link>
    <description>Maps, Hash Tables, and Dictionaries!</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/07-hash-tables/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What are Hash Tables?</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/07-hash-tables/01-hash-table-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/07-hash-tables/01-hash-table-intro/</guid>
      <description>A hash table is an unordered collection of key-value pairs, where each key is unique. The great thing about hash tables is that they provide efficient insertion, removal and lookup operations that arrays and linked lists cannot match, such as:&#xA;Retrieval operations in an unsorted array run in order $N$ time, Retrieval operations in a sorted array using binary search run in constant time, but insertion operations run in order $N$ time, and Insertion operations run in constant time in linked lists, but retrieval operations run in order $N$ time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hash Tables in Code</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/07-hash-tables/02-hash-table-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/07-hash-tables/02-hash-table-code/</guid>
      <description>As stated previously, a hash table has three main components: an array, a hash function, and a set of buckets that store key-value pairs. We discuss the implementation of these below.&#xA;Array We use an array to hold pointers to the buckets where the key-value pairs are stored. While the array itself is a common data type found in almost every language, there are some important aspects to the arrays used in hash tables.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hash Functions</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/07-hash-tables/03-hash-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/07-hash-tables/03-hash-functions/</guid>
      <description>A hash function converts a key into a hash code, which is an integer value that can be used to index our hash table array. Obviously, there are some hash functions that are better than others. Specifically, a good hash function is both easy to compute and should uniformly distribute the keys across our hash table array. Both of these are important factors in how fast our hash table operates, since we compute a hash code each time we insert or get a key-value pair from the hash table.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuples</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/07-hash-tables/04-tuples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/07-hash-tables/04-tuples/</guid>
      <description>Before we can start describing the basic hash table functions, we first need to create a way to handle key-value pairs. We generally refer to any piece of data that has two parts as a tuple. In the case of key-value pairs, our tuple would look like (key, value). Some languages, such as Python, provide built-in support for creating tuples, while others such as Java and C# require us to create our own tuple class, which is easy to do.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hash Table Operations</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/07-hash-tables/05-hash-table-operations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/07-hash-tables/05-hash-table-operations/</guid>
      <description>Hash Table Operations You won’t be asked to implement any of these operations since we will just use the built-in class in our chosen language. However, we want you to se behind the scenes and understand how a hash table is implemented directly in code.&#xA;The HashTable class has three attributes that provide the basic data structure and parameters we need to efficiently manage our table.&#xA;size - captures the number of tuples stored in the table.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hash Table Based Sets</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/07-hash-tables/06-hash-table-sets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/07-hash-tables/06-hash-table-sets/</guid>
      <description>In this section, we walk through the pseudocode for some basic set operations built on our hash table class above. In this new version of the set class, we declare mySet as a hash table and use that throughout our operations.&#xA;mySet = new HashTable() When using a hash table to implement sets, one of the most important choices we must make is what to use for a key. This is really difficult in the case of sets since we do not know exactly what types of objects may be put into the set.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hash Tables Summary</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/07-hash-tables/07-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc310/07-hash-tables/07-summary/</guid>
      <description>In this module, we introduced the concept of a hash table, which is a data structure that provides efficient insertion and retrieval operations. We introduced the three essential elements of hash tables:&#xA;An array that holds buckets where key-value pairs are stored, A hash function that maps a key to a specific array index, and A set of buckets that allow the hash table to store multiple key-value pairs whose keys map to the same index in the array.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>